{"tossups": [{"question": "In 2005, this figure offered his resignation to Larry Lucchino and walked out in a gorilla suit. In 2002, this man was hired for a job that had been turned down by Billy Beane, as described at the end of <em>Moneyball</em>. Tom Ricketts hired this man as President in 2011; with Jed Hoyer, this man brought Anthony Rizzo and Kris Bryant to Wrigley Field. For ten points, name this baseball executive who, as GM and President, ended the World Series droughts of both the Boston Red Sox and Chicago Cubs.", "answer": "Theo<b> Epstein</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "This battle was prompted by faulty intelligence that claimed one side was at Fort Ninety-Six. While attempting to taunt the enemy commander, William Washington had his horse shot out from under him. In this battle, John Eager Howard helped form one of three lines of defense set up by the Broad River to repel an attack from the British Legion under Banastre Tarleton. For ten points, name this 1781 Revolutionary War victory for Daniel Morgan in South Carolina.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Cowpens</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The action at the center of this case was first defined in<em> Stromberg v. California</em>, while the ruling of <em>Bethel v. Fraser</em> was held to be distinct from this case. Abe Fortas\u2019s majority opinion in this case held that the action in question did not cause a disruption and that its participants did not lose their rights\u201cat the schoolhouse gate.\u201d This case dealt with five children who, in 1965, wore black armbands to protest the Vietnam War in Iowa. For ten points, name this Supreme Court case that protected students\u2019 right to free speech.", "answer": "<b> Tinker</b> v. Des Moines (Independent Community School District)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One member of this family became the first woman appointed to the Harvard University faculty and fought typhoid in Chicago from Hull House. Another member of this family served as the Headmistress of the Bryn Mawr college prep school in Baltimore for 26 years, then detailed the \u201cTimeless Tales of Gods and Heroes\u201d in a 1942 work whose first section teaches about Greek creation myths. For ten points, name this family, including public health advocate Alice and classicist Edith, the author of<em> Mythology</em>.", "answer": "<b> Hamilton</b> (accept Alice and/or Edith<b> Hamilton</b>)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "At this location, Ahmad Abdali\u2019s forces defeated Sadashivrao Bhau, though the Durrani Empire opted to retreat regardless. After a victory at Tughlaqabad, Hemu was killed at a battle in this location when Bairam Khan moved to reconquer Delhi. At one battle in this location, one ruler used araba carts to maximize the effect of his artillery against Ibrahim Lodi. For ten points, name this site of a 1526 victory for Babur that marked the beginning of the Mughal dynasty.", "answer": "(Battle(s) of)<b> Panipat</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This mathematician names an exact solution to the Einstein field equation describing swirling dust. He spent time in a sanitarium for a nervous breakdown following the murder of Moritz Schlick by Johann Nelbock, who was pardoned after two years by the Nazis. This mathematician is best known for showing that axiomatic systems cannot prove their own consistency and that all axiomatic systems with a notion of arithmetic will contain unprovable truths. For ten points, give this mathematician who names a set of two incompleteness theorems.", "answer": "Kurt<b> G\u00a8odel</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {"question": "A city in this present-day country along the Irtysh River was the capital of the self-proclaimed Alash Autonomy and was the home of a facility nicknamed \u201cThe Polygon. The Semipalatinsk nuclear test site is in this country, as is a location leased until 2050 by its northern neighbor where Sputnik I was launched. This home of the Baikonur Cosmodrome moved its capital from Almaty in 1997. Astana is now the capital of, for ten points, what former Soviet republic, the largest landlocked country in the world?", "answer": "Republic of<b> Kazakhstan</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This man replaced his superior, Quintus Caecilius Metellus, as the commander of the expedition against Jugurtha. He decisively defeated the Cimbri and the Teutones while serving as consul, a position that he was elected to seven times. In an effort to minimize the baggage train, this man ordered his soldiers to carry their supplies on his back, earning them the nickname of this man\u2019s mules. For ten points, name this Roman general, the first to recruit soldiers from the poor, one of his many military reforms.", "answer": "Gaius<b> Marius</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Poland was forced to exit this war following the Treaty of Altranstadt, which also provided for the execution of the nobleman Johann Patkul. Shortly after a naval engagement at Grengam, this conflict was ended through The Treaty of Nystad. During this conflict, the Cossack leader Ivan Mazepa joined forces with Charles XII, only to be defeated by the forces of Peter the Great. For ten points, name this 18th century conflict in which Russia defeated the Swedish empire.", "answer": "<b> Great Northern</b> War", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Lamassu had the body of these animals and human heads. Two lions attack these animals in reliefs at the entrance to the Apadana of Darius and Xerxes. Four of the extinct ancestor of these animals, called aurochs, were painted using twisted perspective in a \u201cHall\u201d of these animals. Several youths are shown ceremonially leaping over the horns of these animals on the walls of the Palace at Knossos on Crete. For ten points, name this bovine animal that provided the head for the mythical Minotaur.", "answer": "<b> bull</b>s (prompt on cattle or cows)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Early settlers to what is now this state relied on the Ocracoke Inlet for their shipping routes. Its sand dunes at Jockey\u2019s Ridge are the tallest on the East Coast. Settlers of a colony in this state disappeared with only the word \u201cCroatoan\u201d carved into a tree as evidence, and its Kill Devil Hills were the site of the first controlled flight of the Wright Brothers. Kitty Hawk is located on the Outer Banks of, for ten points, what state, home to Roanoke Island and the city of Raleigh?", "answer": "<b> North Carolina</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "This activity, when conducted in a morally incorrect way, was condemned as \u201cnefas\u201d by the Ancient Romans. Augustine used Romans 13:4 to support this activity when conducted by the church. The School of Salamanca attempted to develop a theory of this activity based on Thomas Aquinas\u2019 three conditions for its justification. The rights of<em> jus in bello</em> and<em> jus ad bellum</em> both involve this activity. For ten points, name this general term for an armed conflict between societies.", "answer": "<b> war</b> (prompt on terms regarding violence, force, etc., that don\u2019t use that term; accept just and/or unjust<b> war</b>)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This event was reinforced by Eurymedon and Demosthenes, though their men failed to breach the Epipolae walls. A lunar eclipse convinced one side to linger in a harbor</b> <b>during this event, leaving them exposed to attack from (+)</b> <b>Gylippus. The destruction of</b> <b>the Hermai statues shortly before this campaign led to the recall of one of its leaders, (*) </b>Alcibiades [al-sih-by-ah-deez]. For ten points, name this disastrous campaign of the Peloponnesian War in which Athens tried to invade a large Mdeiterranean island.", "answer": "<b> Sicilian Expedition</b> (accept equivalents for expedition, like<b> Campaign</b>; prompt on the Peloponnesian War before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>Description acceptable. The 2006 film</b><em><b> Long Road to Heaven</b></em><b> describes this event and the ensuing trials of Amrozi and Imam Samudri, who were executed in 2008 for their roles in it. One part of this event was allegedly triggered by Dulmatin\u2019s (+) cell phone. A group led by Riduan Isamuddin perpetrated this event, in which a Mitsubishi L300 loaded with C4 was detonated outside Paddy\u2019s Pub and the (*)</b> Sari Club. Over 200 people were killed in this event, which was carried out by members of Jemaah Islamiyah, a terrorist group based in Southeast Asia. For ten points, name this 2002 bombing, the deadliest terrorist attack in Indonesian history.", "answer": "2002<b> Bali</b> bombing (accept other descriptors; prompt on descriptions of a terrorist attack in Indonesia before \u201cIndonesian\u201d is said)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man hosted a religious debate at his castle of Azuchi, which he built to defend the capital. He used arquebuses against a cavalry attack at the Battle of Nagashino, and he</b> <b>defeated an Imagawa attack into his territory at the Battle of (+)</b> <b>Okehazama. After the</b> <b>treachery of Akechi Mitsuhide, this man was forced to commit suicide in the Incident of Honnoji. (*)</b> Toyotomi Hideyoshi succeeded, for ten points, which daimyo who overthrew the Ashikaga Shogunate, the first \u201cGreat Unifier\u201d of Japan during the Sengoku period?", "answer": "<b> Oda</b> Nobunaga", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>During this battle, the</b><em><b> Minnesota</b></em><b> was struck by stray cannon fire from the James River Squadron. During the battle, an explosion blinded Captain John Worden with paint, forcing his ship to withdraw. In this battle, the (+) USS</b><em><b> Congress</b></em><b> and</b><em><b> Cumberland</b></em><b> were destroyed in an attempt to stop the Anaconda Plan. Catesby ap Roger Jones led the second day of this engagement, in which (*) </b> neither ship suffered significant damage. For ten points, name this Civil War naval battle, the first combat between two ironclad ships.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Hampton Roads</b> (accept descriptions of the battle between the USS<b> Monitor</b> and the USS<b> Merrimack</b>, or between the USS<b> Monitor</b> and the CSS<b> Virginia</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this South American independence leader, nicknamed \u201cThe Liberator.\u201d", "answer": "Simon<b> Bolivar</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man gave a press conference that opened with John Quinn quoting Ben Franklin\u2019s\u201cA republic, sir, if you can keep it\u201d anecdote. Later in the press conference, this man</b> <b>discussed a tax deduction for giving his (+)</b> <b>Vice Presidential papers to the government</b> <b>and misspoke, suggesting that John Ehrlichman was guilty until proven innocent. The press conference climaxed with this man explaining \u201cI have (*) </b> earned everything I have got\u201d after noting that \u201cpeople have got to know whether or not their President is a crook.\u201d For ten points, name this President who was grilled by newspaper editors in 1973 over the Watergate scandal.", "answer": "Richard<b> Nixon</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A revolution in this year began with a sailor mutiny at Kiel. Shortly after resisting Operation Michael and an attack at Georgette in this year, Ferdinand Foch began the Hundred Days campaign. The (+) Spring Offensive of this year was halted when Erich Ludendorff was defeated at the second battle of the Marne. The Hindenburg Line was breached by Allied troops in this year, leading (*)</b> Kaiser Wilhelm II to abdicate the German throne. For ten points, name this year in which World War I ended.", "answer": "<b> 1918</b> (prompt on \u201c18\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}